<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math on Scenic-Shop</title>
    <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/math/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Math on Scenic-Shop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/math/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mathjax test</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2014/2014-02-20-mathjax-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2014/2014-02-20-mathjax-test/</guid>
      <description>This is a test of the new Mathjax plugin. Also, a quick little cheat sheet for right-angle trig identities; useful for calculating component forces of an angular force.
$$ o = h \, \sin \, \theta = a \, \tan \, \theta $$
$$ a = h \, \cos \, \theta = \frac {o}{\tan \, \theta} $$
$$ h = \frac {o}{\sin \, \theta} = \frac {a} {\cos \, \theta} $$</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flattening Cones</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-06-29-flattening-cones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-06-29-flattening-cones/</guid>
      <description>Update: I just updated this frustum calculator with javascript versions that will run from the browser. One will calculate the flattened frustum from the radii, the other uses the circumferences of the frustum shape.
Have you ever wanted to lay out the frustum of a cone on a flat surface?” “A what?” “A frustum, the part of a cone that is left when you lop off the top.” “Oh, yeah. If I had a nickel&amp;hellip; sadly, I’m still poor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Good) Math Links</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-02-05-good-math-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-02-05-good-math-links/</guid>
      <description>Ever wish you were better at math? Me too. I’ve been teaching myself calculus and stumbled on Better Explained, a blog with excellent math explanations. The author’s aim is to make math concepts intuitive. Now I actually understand what the imaginary number ‘i’ is all about; it wasn’t hard at all.
Sure most people think math is boring, but that’s because they probably don’t really “get” it. Don’t worry, it’s not your fault you don’t enjoy math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll Bender Forces Chart</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-01-06-roll-bender-forces-chart/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-01-06-roll-bender-forces-chart/</guid>
      <description>How much force does it take to bend 3”x16ga box tube to a 5’ radius in one pass? What’s the largest steel shape you can jam in a typical scene shop-built manual roll bender without cracking a roller? A week ago I didn’t know the answer to either one of these questions, now I’ve got a pretty good idea.
We’re talking about making a roll bender at work, and are waffling over whether to build a manual or motorized bender.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
