<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Scenic-Shop</title>
    <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Scenic-Shop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Calculators</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/calculators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/calculators/</guid>
      <description>These are a collection of web-based javascript calculators that are mobile friendly. An abbreviated list of the calculators are as follows:
 Unit Conversions Hydrulic Piston Force and Speed Winch Force and Speed Winch Drums Motion &amp;amp; Dynamics ANSI Chain Values, Ratings, Sprocket Distance Bearing PV Shock Load Forces Etc&amp;hellip;  How to Use You can find the web-based calculators here: Calculators
The source is on github in the following repo: Calculators Repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collector</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/collector/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/collector/</guid>
      <description>Designed for use with Autodesk&amp;rsquo;s Inventor iLogic scripts and Autocad LISP files, Collector is intended to allow use of external IDEs such as Visual Studio and support class or module-per-file coding organization.
This is handy for autolisp routines as well, as they can be stored in seperate files but combined into a single lisp file.
It is also useful when developing an Inventor Add-In and you want to perform testing in the iLogic environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InventorShims</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/inventorshims/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/projects/inventorshims/</guid>
      <description>InventorShims is a collection of vb.net code to extend and add common API methods and classes to Autodesk Inventor&amp;rsquo;s existing API.
From simplified methods to interact with iproperties and parameters, to generic methods to return the pertinent document object from a supplied Inventor object type, InventorShims aims to create a library of frequently used methods and classes. These are organized by area of concern, into seperate files; load only what you need.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
