<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>AutoCAD on Scenic-Shop</title>
    <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/autocad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in AutoCAD on Scenic-Shop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/autocad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AutoLISP Layer Snippets</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2020/2020-10-07-autolisp-layer-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2020/2020-10-07-autolisp-layer-snippets/</guid>
      <description>These are some of my frequently used AutoLISP snippets for layer management. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a heap of these in a lisp file that I autoload into autocad at startup. You can find the entire file here: layer-shortcuts.lsp.
If you look through that file, you&amp;rsquo;ll see that I have a common set of layers (for 2D and general work) that I include in every drawing file. The AutoLisp commands help to speed up my drafting with these common layers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch! v. 1.2 released</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2011/2011-05-19-scratch-v-1-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2011/2011-05-19-scratch-v-1-2-released/</guid>
      <description>Scratch - the scratchpad layer utility for AutoCAD - has been updated to version 1.2!
Download Scratch 1.2 here.
Hard to believe its been over a year since I released an update to Scratch. This update is kind of a sea change for the program, see the notes below. On another note, this is the last release I am going to issue; I use it every day, and it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been an active development project for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twist Lisp</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2011/2011-02-08-twist-lisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2011/2011-02-08-twist-lisp/</guid>
      <description>Did you know you can precisely rotate the current view of modelspace? This is a killer way to simplify drafting and dimensioning objects on an angle, especially if you have a way to align the current view to an object. (And we do, keep reading.)
The longhand command is Dview &amp;gt; Dviewblock &amp;gt; Twist. Enter the angle you want to twist the current view to, and you&amp;rsquo;re set. Why type that out every time?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pianos &amp; Steel. CAD Block Giveaway!</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-12-21-pianos-steel-cad-block-giveaway/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-12-21-pianos-steel-cad-block-giveaway/</guid>
      <description>I just realized I never posted those grand piano cad blocks I promised months ago. You can snag them here (version 2k). Egg. face. mine.
While I&amp;rsquo;m at it - this is a link to some commonly used steel profile blocks. Some of them are dynamic, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need a newer (2006? I&amp;rsquo;m too lazy to look it up right now) version of autocad to utilize them. Inside you&amp;rsquo;ll find:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved Layer Isolate</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-07-17-improved-layer-isolate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-07-17-improved-layer-isolate/</guid>
      <description>This Autocad lisp combines the layeriso &amp;amp; layeruniso commands into a single command. Use once to invoke, use again to turn off. You can use fade mode or off mode.
Download and enjoy!
command: LI - layer isolate with Fade Mode @ 60% (default) command: LI` - (that&amp;rsquo;s a backtick, next to the 1 key) layer isolate in Off Mode</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Layer State Switcher</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-07-17-layer-state-switcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-07-17-layer-state-switcher/</guid>
      <description>This AutoCAD lisp command transparently saves the current layerstate. Subsequent invocations switch between the saved state and the current state. You can go back and forth until your eyes pop out.
Download and enjoy!
command: LSS - on first run, it will save a layerstate and exit the command - option: Previous - (default option), saves the current layerstate and switches you to the original saved layerstate. - option: Update - saves the current layerstate for future retrieval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aCAD: Text Override Tool Update</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-05-10-acad-text-override-tool-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-05-10-acad-text-override-tool-update/</guid>
      <description>Download Text Override Tool v2.7 - while in AutoCAD type &amp;ldquo;TO&amp;rdquo; to run this routine.
I&amp;rsquo;ve recently updated my text override tool for AutoCAD. In case you didn&amp;rsquo;t know, you can make the text field in a dimension read anything you want. Ask some hardcore cad users about it, and your castle might be set upon by an angry mob. Why do some drafters revile the text override? Reason: lies, lies, and more damned lies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch! v0.8 Released.</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-02-23-scratch-v0-8-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-02-23-scratch-v0-8-released/</guid>
      <description>Scratch! has been updated to version 0.8.
Download Scratch! v.8
This version adds a couple of features and bug-fixes:
 The AutoCAD text window no longer pops up when running the EST command. Thank goodness, that was annoying. A new confirmation (with a cool view of all items on the temporary layer) has been added to the EST command. This allows you to see what you are deleting before you do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dykes Moulding - CAD Blocks</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-21-dykes-moulding-cad-blocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-21-dykes-moulding-cad-blocks/</guid>
      <description>Looking for a collection of the Dykes Lumber moulding profiles in CAD format? Here you go.
Download the Dykes Moulding file here. (381 kb)
The profiles have been compiled into a single file, each profile a separate block. (Design Center users rejoice!) This file is in v2000 format. Much thanks goes to Adam Godbout for providing the file.
Happy CADDing.
Edit: The following download contains the collection of Dykes profiles in individual dxf files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratch! (An AutoCAD Scratchpad Utility)</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-07-scratch-an-autocad-scratchpad-utility/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-07-scratch-an-autocad-scratchpad-utility/</guid>
      <description>Scratch provides a quick &amp;amp; simple way to utilize a temporary scratchpad layer in AutoCAD. Scratch allows you to quickly switch in &amp;amp; out of the scratchpad layer, and throw it away whenever you want, leaving the rest of your AutoCAD drawing untouched.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been using it for
 transferring geometry building complex shapes (I use the boundary command later to create objects) throwaway dimensions (when estimating &amp;amp; sketching ideas)  Download UPDATE: Scratch v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADalyzer 0.7 Update (AutoCAD Command Counter)</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-06-26-cadalyzer0-6b/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-06-26-cadalyzer0-6b/</guid>
      <description>This is an update to the Cadalyzer script that I posted a few months ago. It will count the number of commands you have used in AutoCAD; it does this by examining your AutoCAD log files. (You can enable log files in AutoCAD’s options dialogue box.)
Cadalyzer 0.7 on GitHub New features are listed below
  Counting mechanism has be rebuilt, the script now computes 25 times faster than the previous version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dykes Moulding - CAD Files</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-05-25-dykes-moulding-cad-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-05-25-dykes-moulding-cad-files/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve downloaded the Dykes Moulding CAD files from their website you may have noticed that the profiles are not to scale. From what I could see, the scale factor seems to be the same for all the files, approximately 0.056568174.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CADalyzer (AutoCAD Command Counter)</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-03-01-cadalyzer-autocad-command-counter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-03-01-cadalyzer-autocad-command-counter/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been working on a Ruby utility to analyze AutoCAD log files. The goal is to count how many times each command is invoked. The basic functionality is all in place, I’ve plans to add more in-depth analysis and perhaps even turn it into a web based tool. For now, you’ll have to download it and run it in the command line. If you want to run this, you’ll need the Ruby programming language runtime installed on your computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acad - Saving Keystrokes!</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-02-acad-saving-keystrokes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-02-acad-saving-keystrokes/</guid>
      <description>(Or: How I Stopped Worring and Learned to Love the Command Alias)
If you are an avid AutoCAD user, you know that setting up your command aliases is key. For those interested, I’ve put my customized portion of the acad.pgp file here.
For those of you who are not familiar with AutoCAD’s command aliases, you’re in for a treat. Every time you enter “rec” instead of “rectangle,” or “l” instead of “line” you are using a command alias.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoCAD LISP routines</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-08-06-autocad-lisp-routines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-08-06-autocad-lisp-routines/</guid>
      <description>I’ve thrown a few of my most frequently used LISP routines on here. You’ll find the files &amp;amp; descriptions here. I will be adding more as I clean them up and determine where I acquired them (so I can give credit where credit is due.) I am also tinkering with the idea of posting my pgp file; while not especially useful, I am always interested to see what shortcuts other people use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AutoCAD Imperial &amp; Metric Conversions</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-07-30-autocad-imperial-metric-conversions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-07-30-autocad-imperial-metric-conversions/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday a friend asked me how to convert an AutoCAD drawing from metric to imperial. He needed to dimension in inches and draw imperial sized objects inside a metric drawing. Turns out the Autocad help is not so helpful on this specific subject.
Units &amp;amp; Units: So here&amp;rsquo;s the deal, AutoCAD “thinks” in a drawing units. These drawing units don’t have a real world size. The only relation to real world size they have is the name that we assign to them in the units dialogue box.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
