<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Solutions on Scenic-Shop</title>
    <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/solutions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Solutions on Scenic-Shop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/tags/solutions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Littlest Track Dog - The Real Thing</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-06-18-littlest-track-dog-the-real-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-06-18-littlest-track-dog-the-real-thing/</guid>
      <description>These are the finished pictures from the tiny track dog project. (Man, that was a long time ago.) And the results were: success! They worked like a charm. There was no cable slip, no binding in the track, and the travel noise was minimal. We noticed that the UHMW bowed (approx 1/32&amp;quot;) at the bottom when the cable was tightened down, which was expected from such small bits of hardware. Nick simply pre-tightened the cable, and carefully shaved the dogs on the tablesaw &amp;ndash; done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Video from Coming Home</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-02-10-new-video-from-coming-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-02-10-new-video-from-coming-home/</guid>
      <description>Just finished editing this video for my portfolio, thought other might find it interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Littlest Track Dog (mark II)</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-01-08-littlest-track-dog-mark-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2010/2010-01-08-littlest-track-dog-mark-ii/</guid>
      <description>This is the mark II design for the tiny track dog I posted earlier. This version features a sandwich style construction, which has several benefits over the mark I design.
Securing the aircraft cable through this dog should be vastly easier than the first version. It&amp;rsquo;s as simple as two set screws, a few copper inserts, and four flat head machine screws. Machining the cable path in the first version wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard, but cleaning meeting two small, blind holes 135 degrees apart did prove a challenge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Littlest Dog Evar?</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-12-24-littlest-dog-evar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-12-24-littlest-dog-evar/</guid>
      <description>Is this the littlest track dog ever? Perhaps. Either way, it&amp;rsquo;s sooo cute! This prototype track dog measures in at 3/4&amp;quot; x 15/32&amp;quot; x 3.5&amp;quot; and is milled from a solid chunk of UHMW. (Ignore the oily grime, its fresh off the bridgeport.) The 1/8&amp;quot; aircraft cable is secured with two set screws in the opposite face of the dog. I&amp;rsquo;m thinking the mark 2 will feature a sandwich style construction with a fixed knife.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guides from Gak</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-24-guides-from-gak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-24-guides-from-gak/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Power Supplies... Revisited</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-20-stock-power-supplies-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-20-stock-power-supplies-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Months ago I wrote a brief ditty about modifying commonly available computer power supplies to power low voltage DC effects. You&amp;rsquo;ll find the original article here. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t completely satisfied with the first one I modified. You can see it in the picture below, it&amp;rsquo;s the ugly one to the left. After perusing a Mouser catalogue this summer, I found what I was looking for - barrier strips with pass-thru terminals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weld-Bearings</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-17-weld-bearings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-17-weld-bearings/</guid>
      <description>You need small, ad hoc, weld-on bearings? Check this out. Use a plastic bushing, a shaft collar and a cone-point socket set screw. Weld the shaft collar over a hole, and keep the plastic bushing in place with the set screw (the cone point is key). Feel free to add a little threadlocker if you&amp;rsquo;re paranoid. Works like a charm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secondhand Monopod</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-14-secondhand-monopod/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-14-secondhand-monopod/</guid>
      <description>I like to take detailed pictures of the scene designer&amp;rsquo;s model for each set we build. Inevitably the director and stage managers want the model in rehearsal, and it becomes difficult to share. Things get really hairy when the scenic charge wants a piece of the action.
Obviously, the stiller the camera, the clearer the picture. I set out to find a secondhand something I could use as a monopod. Let this be a lesson: ask a prop person for a monopod, and you&amp;rsquo;ll get a showerhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism Resources</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-11-mechanism-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-11-11-mechanism-resources/</guid>
      <description>This one&amp;rsquo;s for the mech heads and purveyors of fine machinery.
Cornell University’s Reuleaux Collection is a collection of 220 machines. The machines include various crank mechanisms, couplings, linkages, compound gearing&amp;hellip; the list goes on. The website itself is a catalogue of the 19th century machines - some with accompanying videos and technical documentation. In my opinion, the machines themselves are functional, beautifully crafted works of art; they deserve some attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mirrored Flats: A Learning Experience</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-05-25-mirrored-flats-a-learning-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-05-25-mirrored-flats-a-learning-experience/</guid>
      <description>Found out a couple of pitfalls when building flats with mirrored acrylic skins. Our usual acrylic adhesive is a two part methacrylate based adhesive. It works incredibly well when bonding acrylic to just about any substrate (steel, wood, other plastics&amp;hellip;) Some formulations cure to a relatively clear finish, which is quite the selling point. Unfortunately, we found that methacrylates will distort the mirror coating on mirrored plexi. Whoops. You can see the distortion in the picture below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slick Edging</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-04-09-slick-edging/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-04-09-slick-edging/</guid>
      <description>Here’s another choice for edging a deck and other scenic elements: paper. We recently did a production of Bad Dates and the designer wanted a smooth black finish for the “cut” edges of the walls and deck. Since the audience was sitting only four feet from the set, we experimented with wallpapering with a 50# black kraft paper. The advantages were as follows.
 the paper is thin enough to make the edges very clean the texture was very flat, smooth and consistent - much like bristol board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Power Supplies for Effects</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-04-09-stock-power-supplies-for-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-04-09-stock-power-supplies-for-effects/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a quick post on using computer power supplies to power DC effects.
Pull a power supply out of a computer and go to town! The most common computer power supplies (ATX form factor) provide several different DC voltages, such as +3v, -3v, +5v, -5v, +12v, and -12v. Mix and match between those specific wires or the common and you’ve got most of your onstage effects covered. For example, for our current show we’re using the +12v and -12v leads to power several 24v solenoid valves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Load Wheels</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-02-16-load-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-02-16-load-wheels/</guid>
      <description>File this under great hardware finds. - I needed low-profile, high capacity wheels for an effect and stumbled onto these. They are load wheels for a pallet jack (the wheels pictured are Crown part number 44506 / McMaster 2670T58. The yellow caster mounts are shop built.)
44506 Load wheel specs:
 2500 lbs load rating! 3” diameter x 3 7/8” wide Roller ball bearings Shore 90A polyurethane tread Slightly oversized 3/4” shaft (about 25/32”) $30 each from Mcmaster $45 each from a Crown distributor (price will undoubtably vary)  What makes these attractive?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll Bender Wheels</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-01-21-roll-bender-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2009/2009-01-21-roll-bender-wheels/</guid>
      <description>Danger Will Robinson! The cast iron wheels pictured below are the ones that were spec’ed in Keith Cornelius’s 1997 Tech Expo article_An Inexpensive, Human-Powered Roll-Former_. (Grainer part numbers are #3G262 and #3G263.) Obviously they’ve changed a little bit since 1997; the new “feature” is a crown to the surface of the wheel. Unless you’re looking to mangle your steel whilst bending, I suggest you find flatter wheels.
I suggest finding flatter iron wheels through Mcmaster-Carr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Porta-band Thoughts</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-12-15-additional-porta-band-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-12-15-additional-porta-band-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Quick thought on the porta-band stand described in an earlier post, mounting the saw to the vice-mount takes a couple of minutes. You could make a smaller custom foot that always stays on the saw and “dovetails” into the vice mount. A single machine screw could be used to secure the small foot to the mount. This way the saw could go from case to vice (and back again) in under 30 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porta-band Stand on the Cheap</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-12-11-porta-band-stand-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-12-11-porta-band-stand-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Ian made this custom foot for the Porta-band that clamps into the vice this past week. Its 3/8” cold roll plate with a bit of scrap 1x box tube welded to the underside. A spring clamp on the trigger acts as a low tech on/off switch. .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paste &amp; Punch Templates</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-11-28-paste-punch-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-11-28-paste-punch-templates/</guid>
      <description>While in grad school I became a fan of what I like to call Past &amp;amp; Punch Templates. When you need to fabricate a part that is particularly funky or needs to be exceedingly precise, you print a full sized drawing from CAD and past it onto the material that needs to be machined. Fairly simple right? For years I’ve used spray 77 to adhere the template to the part, but then you have to deal with removing the adhesive from the part when it is going to be painted or moves against another part.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dirt on Stage</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-13-dirt-on-stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-13-dirt-on-stage/</guid>
      <description>Dirt on stage. Poo poo. Dusty, dirty, a real pain in the ass. Jen tells me that she’s got a way to tame the dust. The secret is glycerol (aka glycerine or glycerin). Don’t worry, glycerol may sound threatening, but rest assured, it is not. It is a sugar alcohol that is found in everything from food to pharmaceuticals. Obligatory wiki link to glycerol. You can buy glycerol in 5 gallon buckets, which should last most folks for an entire run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flicker Candle Movies</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-11-flicker-candle-movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-11-flicker-candle-movies/</guid>
      <description>Good news everybody! I’ve finally posted movies of the flicker candles in action. Jeez, that took long enough. Build info here.
flicker_light
flicker_dark</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivoting Success!</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-02-pivoting-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-10-02-pivoting-success/</guid>
      <description>Update for “Pivot Puck” post. &amp;ndash; We installed the pivoting masking wall today, and it was a smashing success. Pivot pucks are definitely going into our stock inventory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Pivoting...</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-09-18-more-pivoting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-09-18-more-pivoting/</guid>
      <description>Continuing in the pivoting vein, these are the pivot points we are using for the top of the masking walls I mentioned above. If you haven’t seen the half cheesebouroughs before, they are hard to beat when attaching stuff to pipe.
edit: Oh yeah, you can find them at BMI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivot Puck</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-09-18-pivot-puck/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-09-18-pivot-puck/</guid>
      <description>We need to pivot a few masking walls for our upcoming production of Hughie. So this little UHMW bugger was born; I like to call it a pivot puck. Screw the puck to a surface and place a shaft in it (our shaft is welded to plate steel that bears on the top surface of the puck) and you’ve got an instant pivot point! (Just make sure the screw heads are countersunk below the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brighter Flicker Candles</title>
      <link>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-07-01-brighter-flicker-candles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://scenic-shop.com/mark6/posts/2008/2008-07-01-brighter-flicker-candles/</guid>
      <description>Is anyone satisfied with the way that flicker candles look on stage? If you didn&amp;rsquo;t raise your hand, then read on. If you did raise your hand, well, keep reading anyways. On the surface, this article is about designing &amp;amp; building a bright, adjustable flicker candle. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you in on a secret: the candle itself is only a foil. Dig deeper and you will find the untapped potential (in most theatres) of the hardware at the heart of the effect: an open source microprocessor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
